Guide to the Clarence Stein papers, 1905-1983.
Stein, Clarence papers
- Series IV. General File
  - 1940-1950
    - New Towns, 1940-1950, Misc. notes and material, 1947-1951, 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      Eric Carlson, Carl Feiss, Tracey B. Augur, Roger Willcox, Robert Weaver (Housing and Home Finance Administrator), Marie McGuire (PHA), Catherine Bauer,
      U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Public Building, Committee on Public Works, Regional Development Council of American, American Institute. of Planners, Subcommittee on Housing of the House Committee on Banking and Currency, RPA
    - Future Development of Our Cities (Memo to Holtzendorff), 1944 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      Harold L. Holtzendorff
      memo
    - County of London Plan, comments by CSS, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 35)
      paper
  - 1942
    - CSS Honors and Testimonials and old lists of jobs, 1941-1942, 1955-1963 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      Alexander Bing, Roy Lubove
      correspondence, articles, drafts, revisions, resumes, biographical sketches
  - Community Planning, 1942-1944
    - Community Facilities, Defense Housing Plan Types, Suggested, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 37)
      plans, blueprints
    - Community Facilities -- F.P.H.A. Review, 1942, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 38)
      community facility studies, infirmary plans, nursery schools
      Charles Butler and Addison Erdman, Herbert Emmerick (Comm. NHA), Lee F. Johnson, Robert D. Kohn
      Federal Public Housing Authority, National Housing Agency
      correspondence, contract, reports, notes, drawings
    - Community Equipment: Nursery Schools, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Schools, 1942-1944 (Box 7, Folder 40)
      nurseries, day care facilities in war housing communities
      Children's Bureau Conference On Day Care of Children of Working Mothers
      notes, plans, reports, outlines
    - Community Facilities, 1943-1949 (Box 7, Folder 41)
      community centers
      Catherine Bauer Wurster, Louise Blackham, Lewis Mumford
      notes, outlines, drafts
    - Building New Communities, L.A., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 42)
      education, cost of local government, spacious community centers, outline of building new communities, operation maintenance costs, public health, Lee F. Johnson to CSS
      outlines, drafts, memo
    - Community Planning -- Size Standards, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 43)
      outlines, notes
    - School -- Neighborhood Units, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 44)
      education planning, neighborhood size
      notes, outlines, revisions
    - Community Organization and Services, 1934, 1943-1944 (Box 7, Folder 45)
      notes of Louise Blackham meetings, 1944
      notes, charts
    - Community Development, Last N.T. Diagrams, 1948, 1959-1966 (Box 7, Folder 46)
      community facilities requirements
      diagrams, correspondence, notes, map, charts
  - COSTS, 1942-1944
    Land, Construction Site Development, Maintenance and Operation Costs for Housing
    - Municipal or Government Costs, 1933-1937, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 47)
      T.O. Walker (Radburn Assoc.), Charles S. Ascher, Ralph Eberlin
      Public Administration Clearing House
      correspondence, memos, notes, article, charts
  - COSTS
    - Costs, general 1942, 1931-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
      apartment room rentals
      charts, blueprints, memos
  - COST STUDIES
    - Miscellaneous, 1929-1940 (Box 7, Folder 49)
      garage, maintenance, landscaping, room rental
      report, including cost estimates, tables, memos, correspondence
  - COST STUDIES
    - "A Report on Methods of Reducing the Cost of Construction in Large-Scale Housing Projects", 1941 (Box 7, Folder 50)
      Citizen's Housing Council of New York
  - COST STUDIES
    - Maintenance Costs including Phipps, Sunnyside, Radburn, Hillside, 1933-1935, 1940, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 51)
      Ralph Eberlin, Henry Wright
      correspondence, charts, memos, cost estimates
  - COST STUDIES
    - Maintenance and Operation Costs -- Housing, 1933, 1941-1948, undate (Box 7, Folder 52)
      correspondence, notes, memos, charts, cost estimates
  - COST STUDIES
    - Construction Costs, Resettlement Administration Report, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 53)
      Ralph Eberlin, Ralph J. Walker
      memos, cost estimates
  - COST STUDIES
    - Construction Costs, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - COST STUDIES, 1942
    - Developments, Theoretical, Cost of, 1932-1943 (Box 7, Folder 55)
      costs of housing developments
      memos, charts, correspondence
  - COST STUDIES
    - Land Costs, 1933-1939 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      Catherine Bauer, W.F.R. Ballard
      charts, notes
  - COST STUDIES
    - Improvement Costs, Resettlement Administration Report, 1929-1941 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      Ralph Eberlin, O. Kline Fulmer (Greenbelt area)
      memos, reports, charts, cost estimates
  - COST STUDIES
    - Small House Costs, 1928-1941 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      Henry Wright, Samuel Ratensky
      charts, speech, tables, cost estimates
  - COST STUDIES
    - Apartment House Costs, 1921, 1931-1940 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      Henry Wright, Ralph Eberlin
      cost estimates, charts, blueprints, memos, reports
  - COST STUDIES
    - Details of Schemes, Resettlement Administration Report, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      cost estimates, blueprint, drawing
  - COST STUDIES
    - Financial Set-Ups, 1932-1938 (Box 7, Folder 61)
      financing housing developments, slum clearance
      W.F.R. Ballard
      cost estimates, charts, memos
  - COST STUDIES
    - Financial Set-Ups, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 62)
      mortgaging, application for Radburn financing
      Frank E. Vitolo, Catherine Bauer, Robert D. Kohn
      cost estimate, charts, memos, correspondence
  - COST STUDIES
    - Miscellaneous Financial Set-Ups, 1935-1941 (Box 7, Folder 63)
      subsidies, theoretical financial set-ups
      Samuel Ratensky, Frank E. Vitolo, Henry Klaber
      cost estimates, charts, memos, notes, tables
  - COST STUDIES
    - Housing Authority Projects, Confidential Report, January 1940 (Box 7, Folder 64)
      W.W. Davies
      New York City Housing Authority
      memo, graphs, charts, cost estimates
  - COST STUDIES
    - Maintenance & Operational Costs -- Limited Div. Projects, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 65)
      George Brown (Mutual Insurance)
      memo, financial statements, cost estimates, charts
  - COST STUDIES
    - Maintenance & Operational Costs -- N.Y, State Projects, 1939, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 66)
      N.Y. State Board of Housing Projects, Lavanburg Foundation
      charts, memo
  - COST STUDIES
    - "Maintenance and Operating Costs Study", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 67)
      W.W. Davies (CSS Research Assistant)
      study
  - COST STUDIES
    - "Cost of Construction Jobs designed by CSS", 1919-1938 (Box 7, Folder 68)
      construction costs
      financial reports
    - Business Booms and Depressions with reference to Building Projects, 1948, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      charts
    - N.Y. State Study by CSS of State-Aided Housing Developments (for Ira Robbins), 1942, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Ira S. Robbins (Acting State Commissioner of Housing)
      report, outline, diagram, article
    - Housing Laws -- New York State, 1932-1933, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      correspondence, memo, copy of legislative bill, report, outline
    - Division of Housing -- State of New York, 1939, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Edward Weinfeld, State Superintendent of Housing
      cost estimates, notes, correspondence, memo
    - New York State Division of Planned Development, CSS Proposal For 1943-5, 1943-1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Martin P. Catherwood, Com. of Commerce, Elliott V. Bell, State Superintendent of Banks
      Citizens' Housing Council
      proposal, correspondence, drafts, outlines, summary reports, clippings, legislative bill
    - New York State Planned Development plus Preparatory Material, Letters of Comment on the Plan, Memos of 1926 and 1931 to Gov. Roosevelt, 1926, 1931, 1943-1948 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Thomas E. Dewey, Benjamin H. Kizer
      proposal, memo, correspondence, legislative bill, clipping
    - Proposal for a Division of Planned Development in the Executive Department of the State of New York, 1931-1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Citizens Union, RDCA
      memos, outlines, proposal, lectures
  - Study -- Museum of State of New York -- 1944
    - Proposed Museum of the State of New York, 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Study -- Museum of State of New York -- 1944
    - New York State Museum -- Diagrams and Plans, 1939, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      drawings, notes, memos, charts
    - New York State Museum -- Conferences, 1944-1947 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Dr. Carl E. Guthe, Director of Museum
      memos, reports
    - New York State Museum -- Correspondence, 1939-1948 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Lewis Mumford, Francis T. Spauling (Comm. of Education), Charles Adams (Dir., N.Y.S. Museum)
      State Education Department
  - REGIONAL PLANNING ASSOCIATION OF AMERICA
    - RPAA, 1923, 1930-1938 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Lewis Mumford, Stuart Chase, Benton MacKaye
      Hudson Guild
      minutes, treasurer's reports, memos, papers, programs, outlines
    - Regional Development Council of America, "Regional Dispersal for Defense and Peace", 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Washington dispersal, defense housing
      Albert Mayer, Lewis Mumford
      Senate Committee on Banking and Currency
      minutes, memos, membership lists, charts, legislative bill
    - R.D.C.A. Dispersal, Minutes -- Memos, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      trading estates, Washington dispersal
      Donald and Astrid Manson
      Citizens Union, Shag Club
      programs, memos, minutes, drafts, article
    - Regional Planning Association of America (Amalgamated Bank of N.Y. ) Finances, 1942-1948, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      Roger Willcox, Lewis Mumford
      correspondence, financial statement, statements of account
    - RDCA -- Membership, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      Catherine Bauer Wurster, John Gans, Frederick Biggers, Lewis Mumford
      correspondence, membership lists, memos, minutes, programs, budget
    - RDCA: Publicity, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      re: Washington dispersal
      clipping, correspondence, articles
    - R.D.C.A. Purpose and Bylaws, 1948-1951 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      dispersal, transportation
      Benton MacKaye, Lewis Mumford, Albert Mayer, Edward Weinfeld (President, National Public Housing Conference)
      National Public Housing Conference, Inc.
      memos, speeches, notes, correspondence, by-laws
    - R.P.A.A. (loose leaf), 1923-1933, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      Regional Plan Association of America
      Benton MacKaye, Lewis Mumford
      minutes, finances, policy statements, correspondence, memos
  - RDCA
    - Regional Development Council of America, Inc. (looseleaf ), 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      Clarence S. Stein, president
      Regional Development Council of America
      minutes
  - RDCA
    - Regional Development Council of America, Inc. (looseleaf), 1950-1955 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      minutes, membership lists
  - "Shopping Center Studies, 1948, Ventura, LaBrea, etc:
    - Store Reports, Stein--Ratensky, "Commercial Facilities in Defense Housing Projects", 1942 (Box 8, Folder 22)
      Samuel Ratensky (Assoc.)
    - Shopping Centers -- Theory and Notes -- CSS, 1929-1948 (Box 8, Folder 23)
      Robert M. Lillibridge (CHA)
      1929-1932, 1940, 1946-1948
      National Housing Agency, Chicago Housing Authority
      drawings, memos, notes, reports, correspondence
    - Shopping Center, LaBrea, Baldwin Hills, L.A., 1948, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
      Lewis Wilson
      plans, notes, correspondence, drawings
    - Shopping Centers, Truesdale, L.A. annd Harvey, L.A., 1948 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Ventura. Photographs. Nowicki (Joshua Marks), 1948 (Box 8, Folder 26)
      Joshua Marks Company
      photographs, drawings, plans, memos, notes
  - Shopping Center Studies
    - Regional Shopping Centers: Economic Study, 1947, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
      Kenneth Welch, Julian Whittlesey
      National Retail Recentralization, Inc.
      charts, correspondence, memos, report
    - Apartments (New) Queensview with George Brown, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      George D. Brown (Housing Division, Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York)
      correspondence, preliminary plans
    - Proposed Investigation of New Communities for AIA Comm. of Urban Development, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      new towns investigation
    - Baltimore Housing Authority, Seminar, 1949, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      Ralph Eberlin, Oliver C. Winston (Executive Director HA of BC)
      Housing Authority of Baltimore City, Jamison and Marcks
    - Redevelopment (Carl Feiss), Advisor to Community Planning Branch of Housing and Home Finance Agency, 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      slum clearance and urban redevelopment
      Ralph Walker (Subcomm. Redevelopment Program), Albert Mayer, N.S. Keith (Director, Slum Clearance and Urban Redevelopment, H&HFA), George Dugger (City Planning Dept., SF ), Paul Opperman (ExDirector, SF Planning Commission), Carl Feiss (Chief, Comm. Planning and Development Branch, Housing and Home Finance Agency)
      Housing and Home Finance Agency
      correspondence, memos, notes, agendas, article, newsletter
  - Paris and Venice, Essays. Nancy, 1950
    - Nancy, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      correspondence, notes, drawings, plans
    - Nancy, Paris, illustrations, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      parks
      drawings, plans, pictures
    - Paris -- Drawings -- CSS, 1950 and notes, 1950-1960 (Box 8, Folder 34)
      plans, notes, postcards, drafts, maps, articles
    - "Paris As a Contemporary City", 1950 (Box 8, Folder 35)
      drafts, plans, notes
    - Venice, [not all in English], ca. 1950 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      notes, postcards, maps, plan
    - "Venice As a Contemporary City", 1950, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      drafts, revision, drawings, notes, correspondence
    - Prop. Department of City Design, University of Pennsylvania, 1950-1963 (Box 8, Folder 38)
      G. Holmes Perkins (Chairman, Dept. Regional Planning, Harvard), Albert Mayer, Lewis Mumford
      Graduate School of Design, Harvard University
      memo, correspondence
    - Proposed Program of A.T.A. Committee on Urban Design and Housing, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 39)
      Albert Mayer (chairman)
      proposed program
    - General Services Administration, C.S. Stein Consultant, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 40)
      Frederick P. Clark, Tracy B. Augur (Urban Planning Officer, GSA)
      clipping, correspondence, vouchers, memos
  - Washington Dispersal, 1950
    - Washington Dispersal of Essential Government Functions, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 41)
      Frederick P. Clark, Louis Justement, Dr. Abel Wolman (consultants), Jess Larson, GSA Administrator, Tracey Auger
      Office of the Urban Planning Officer, General Services Administration
      draft report and minutes
    - "Washington Dispersal: Decentralization, February 1956 (Box 8, Folder 42)
      notes, maps, outlines
    - Washington Dispersal -- RDCA, 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 43)
      Lewis Mumford, Benton MacKaye, Albert Mayer, Fritz Gutheim
      Regional Development Council of America, Inc., U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Public Buildings Committee on Public Works
      notes, outlines, memos, minutes, legislative bill, drafts, revisions, correspondence
    - Washington for Dispersal, 1961, 1948-1962 (Box 8, Folder 44)
      Congressman Henry S. Reuss, Tracy B. Augur (Urban Planning Officer, GSA), Frederick Clark (NYRPA), Jess Larson, GSA Administrate Benton MacKaye, Roy Bessey, U.S. Dept. of the Interior, Sen. Spessard L. Holland
      General Services Administration, New Towns Committee, American Institute of Planners
      clipping, press releases, correspondence, outlines, reports, drafts, legislative bills notes
    - FCH Co.(Roger Willcox) Gen. 1950 Foundation for Cooperative Housing, 1953-1965 (Box 8, Folder 45)
      new cooperative housing in Honduras and Chatham Village, Sweden, and new cooperative housing programs
      Roger Willcox, Wallace J. Campbell (Pres, FC Winslow Carlton (Pres., FCH), Charles B. Nutting (Dir.,) David L. Krooth
      Agency for International Development, The Buhl Foundation
  - California: Los Angeles, San Fernando, Santa Clara.
    - California -- CSS, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 46)
      Milton Breifogel
    - L.A., Baldwin Hills Village, San Fernando Valley, Public Beach, L.A. City and County Plans, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 47)
      notes, drafts, map, drawings, notice
    - California, 1930, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 48)
      planned development
      Karl J. Belser
      notes, correspondence, legislative bill, drafts, charts
    - Los Angeles City, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 49)
      Regional Planning Commission
    - Los Angeles County, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 50)
      open spaces, dispersal, development
      notes, clippings, outlines
    - Los Angeles and Environs: L.A. County, Orange County, San Fernando County, 1951-1957 (Box 8, Folder 51)
      Milton Breivogel (Director of Planning, Regional Planning Commission)
      map, correspondence, notes, outlines
    - San Fernando Valley, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 52)
      planned development, comparison of growth: L.A. and Stockholm, San Fernando Valley and Vallingby
      notes, outline
    - San Fernando Valley, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 53)
      notes, charts, maps, report, article, outline
    - Los Angeles: War Housing, 1943-1944 (Box 8, Folder 54)
      outline, memo
    - A New Community, L.A., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 55)
      requirements for a new community
      memo, notes
    - Apartment Houses, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 56)
      high rise structures in L.A.
      Lewis Mumford, Catherine Bauer
      Metropolitan Recreation and Youth Services Council, Los Angeles City Housing Authority
      reports, memos, correspondence, notes, outlines, drafts
    - New Towns -- California, 1951, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 57)
      planned new developments
      Tracy B. Augur, William Pereira
      Regional Development Council of America, Inc.
      reports, notes, article
  - Santa Clara County, California, 1956
    - Santa Clara County, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 58)
      open space
      William H. Whyte, Jr.
    - Santa Clara County, 1956-1963 (Box 8, Folder 59)
      zoning, land preservation, general plan
      Planning Dept., County of Santa Clara
      notes, report, correspondence, proposals, diagram, legislative bill, article
    - Santa Clara County -- Handscript, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      planned development and preservation
    - [Untitled] Santa Clara County, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      generalized development plan for Santa Clara County
    - [Untitled] Santa Clara County, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 62)
      preservation of agriculture in Santa Clara County
    - Santa Clara County (Box 8, Folder 63)
      regional planning and development, preservation of agricultural land
      notes, correspondence, outlines
    - [Untitled] Santa Clara County, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 64)
      visits to Santa Clara County
      Ken Wilhelm, Karl Belser, Prof. R. Young
    - Santa Clara County, C.S. Stein, 1957, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      planning and regional development
      Milton Breivogel
      report, including outlines, notes, drafts, revisions, correspondence, references, maps
    - [Untitled] Santa Clara County, 1957-1962, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
      general plans, proposals, inventory for Santa Clara County
      County of Santa Clara Planning Commission
      pamphlets, maps
  - Disposal of Greenbelt Towns, 1951-53
    - Greenbelt, 1961-1962, 1944-1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      disposal, cooperatives
      David Krooth (lawyer for FCH and Greenbelt), Julian Whittlesey, Charles T. McDonald (City Manager, Greenbelt)
      1944, 1949, 1952-1953, 1961-1964
      notes, legislative bills, correspondence, map, pamphlet, clipping/ memos, maps
    - Cine. Comm. Dev. Co. (American Legion) Greenhills, Forest View Estates, File Greenhills, 1949-1960, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Lawrence Tucker
      Cincinnati Community Development Program
      plans, articles, notes, prospectus, pamphlets, correspondence, outline, map
    - Disposal of GB Towns, 1947-1950 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      John Egan (Commission, Public Housing Administration), Paul Douglas (Senator), Lawrence Tucker (CCDC), Walter E. Kroening (Community Manager, Greendale, Charles T. McDonald
      Cincinnati Community Development Company, American Legion Community Development Corp.
      memos, legislative bills, correspondence, clippings, maps, photo, proposals
    - Greenbelt Disposal, Stein and Mayer and Whittlesey, 1949-1951 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      David Krooth, Julian Whittlesey, John Egan
      memo, notes, correspondence, proposal
    - Greenbelt Disposal, 1947-1949, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Walter E. Koenig, John Egan
      American Legion Community Development Corp.
      articles, correspondence, clippings, resolutions, plans, map
    - The Greenbelt Towns, July 1948 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      draft, outline
    - CSS, Resettlement Report, Interleaved with Greendale Data, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
      index
    - Green Hills -- Extra copies of articles, etc., 1947-1948, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
      map, negative, charts, notes
    - Policy Plan of Land Use for Greenbelt, Maryland prepared by F.C.H. Company, Inc., Copy No. 12 -- C.S. Stein, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Winston Carlton (Pres., FCH)
      Foundation for Cooperative Housing
      report with map
    - Greenhill -- Operation -- Maintenance, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
      operation maintenance costs of 3 Greenbelt towns
    - National Housing Agency, Federal Public Housing Authority, Greenhills Project, Analysis of Operating and Maintenance Costs by Fiscal Years 1940 thru 1944 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      n.c.
    - Memos Greenbelt Disposal, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Stein memos
    - CSS Notes Greenbelt Disposal, 1948-1949, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
      notes, drafts
    - Greenbelt Disposal, 1947-1951 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      Charles T. McDonald, Walter E. Kroenig, Orvil Olmstead (Regional Director)
      Subcommittee on Housing and Rents of the of the Senate Banking and Currency Committee
      report, outlines, correspondence, articles, memos, legislative bills
    - Correspondence. Greenbelt Disposal, 1947-1950 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      Lee F. Johnson (National Housing Conference), Paul H. Douglas (U.S. Sen., Labor and Public Welfare), Walter Kroenig, Catherine Bauer Wurster, William Wurster, D.S. Myer (Comm. Fed. Public Housing Agency), David Krooth, Albert Mayer
      Correspondence, clippings
    - Disposal of Greenbelt Towns, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      John Egan, Charles T. McDonald, Walter E. Kroenig
      Housing and Home Finance Agency, PHA, Subcommittee on Housing and Rents of the Senate Banking and Currency Committee
      correspondence, notes, charts, memo, article, legislative bill
    - Greenbelt Whittlesey, 1947, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      Julian Whittlesey, David L. Krooth, Dillon S. Myer (Comm. PHA)
      Correspondence, notes, memos
    - Greenbelt Disposal -- Second Phase, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      David L. Krooth, Lawrence Tucker/ John L. Egan
      correspondence, reports, clipping, memos, notes
    - Greenbelt Cooperative, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      David L. Krooth
    - Greenbelt Disposal, Senate and House Bills, Committee Members, N.Y. Congressmen, 1949, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      Paul H. Douglas
      National Public Housing Conference
      outline, memo, list, correspondence, drafts, amendments
    - Policy Plan of Land Use for Greenbelt, Maryland prepared by F.C.H. Company, Inc. 1953, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      Foundation for Cooperative Housing, Inc.
    - Greenbelt, 1947, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      Julian Whittlesey, Roger Willcox, David L. Krooth